module.exports = [
  {
    question: 'From the old testament, who was Ruth’s mother-in-law?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Ophrah' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Naomi' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Leah' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Martha' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: 'From the book of Ruth, Naomi had two sons who had wives, the name of the first was Orpah, the second Ruth.'
  },
  {
    question: 'From the old testament, how many cows did the Pharoah dream which signified the years of famine?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: '5' },
      { id: 2, text: '6' },
      { id: 3, text: '7' },
      { id: 4, text: '8' }
    ],
    answer: 3,
    note: 'From Genesis 41, the pharoah saw two dreams. In his dream he saw 7 cows. The head cupbearer then remembered Joseph from prison.'
  },
  {
    question: 'The three friends who tried to comfort Job were named - Bildad, Zophar and ...?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Eliphaz' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Elihu' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Joash' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Hezekiah' }
    ],
    answer: 1,
    note: 'From Job 2, three friend of Job traveled from their country to comfort Job. Eliphaz from Teman, Bildad from Shuhah and Zophar from Naamath'
  },
  {
    question: 'From Psalm 1, when you delight in God’s word and read the scriptures day and night, you are like what?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'A gem among stones' },
      { id: 2, text: 'A tree planted by the river' },
      { id: 3, text: 'A wise man among trouble makers' },
      { id: 4, text: 'A rock in the wind' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: 'From Psalm 1 - You’re a tree replanted by the river, bearing fresh fruit every month.'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the last and final word from the book of the Ecclesiastes?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Gather knowledge.' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Do your best in life.' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Honor and enjoy your Creator.' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Fear God. Do what He tells you.' }
    ],
    answer: 4,
    note: 'From Ecclesiastes 12 - The last and final word is this: Fear God. Do what He tells you. And that’s it.'
  },
  {
    question: 'Isaiah was a prophet during the time of - Uzziah, Jotham, Ahaz and ...?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Joash' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Solomon' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Hezekiah' },
      { id: 4, text: 'David' }
    ],
    answer: 3,
    note: 'From Isaiah 1:1 - The vision that Isaiah son of Amoz saw regarding Judah and Jerusalem during the times of the kings of Judah: Uzziah, Jotham, Ahaz, and Hezekiah.'
  },
  {
    question: 'Matthew 1 mentions the family tree of Jesus. Who was Jesus’ grandfather?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Matthan' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Jacob' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Amon' },
      { id: 4, text: 'David' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: 'From Matthew 1 - ...Matthan had Jacob, Jacob had Joseph, Mary’s husband'
  },
  {
    question: 'According to Jesus what is easier than for the rich and "have it all" to enter the kingdom of God?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'to find a diamond in a coal field' },
      { id: 2, text: 'to plant a tree in the sea' },
      { id: 3, text: 'to move a mountain' },
      { id: 4, text: 'for a camel to go through a needle' }
    ],
    answer: 4,
    note: 'From Mark 10: You can’t imagine how difficult. I’d say it’s easier for a camel to go through a needle’s eye than for the rich to get into God’s kingdom.'
  },
  {
    question: '"For God so loved the world that he gave his one and only Son, that whoever believes in him shall not perish but have eternal life". This famous verse is from ...?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Matthew 6:5' },
      { id: 2, text: 'John 3:16' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Mark 10:13' },
      { id: 4, text: 'John 6:12' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: 'John 3:16 - "For God so loved the world that he gave his one and only Son, that whoever believes in him shall not perish but have eternal life"'
  },
  {
    question: 'For I am convinced that neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither the present nor the future, nor any powers, neither height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God that is in Christ Jesus our Lord',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Is from Romans 8' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Is from Romans 9' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Is from Acts 5' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Is from Philippians 3' }
    ],
    answer: 1,
    note: 'Romans 8:38 says that we are "more than conquerors" with Christ - If God is for us, who can be against us.'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the very last verse of the Bible?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Don’t seal the words of the prophecy of this book!' },
      { id: 2, text: 'The grace of the Master Jesus be with all of you. Amen!' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Only those whose names are written in the Lamb’s Book of Life will get in.' },
      { id: 4, text: 'I saw a Great White Throne and the One Enthroned.' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: 'Revelation 22:21 - The grace of the Master Jesus be with all of you. Amen!'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the last book of the Old Testament?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Haggai' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Nahum' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Malachi' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Micah' }
    ],
    answer: 3,
    note: 'The book of prophet Malachi is the last book in the Old Testament.'
  },
  {
    question: 'In Luke 7, Jesus visits which village where he raises a widow’s only son?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Capernaum' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Nazareth' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Galilee' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Nain' }
    ],
    answer: 4,
    note: 'From Luke 7:11 - When Jesus saw her, his heart broke. He said to her, “Don’t cry.” Then he went over and touched the coffin. He said, “Young man, I tell you: Get up.” The dead son sat up and began talking. Jesus presented him to his mother.'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which chapter of 1 Corinthians talks about love?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: '12' },
      { id: 2, text: '13' },
      { id: 3, text: '14' },
      { id: 4, text: '15' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: '1 Corinthians 13 talks about love - "If I speak with human eloquence and angelic ecstasy but don’t love, I’m nothing but the creaking of a rusty gate."'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which is the longest Psalm?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: '119' },
      { id: 2, text: '120' },
      { id: 3, text: '121' },
      { id: 4, text: '122' }
    ],
    answer: 1,
    note: 'Psalm 119 has 176 verses and talks mainly about the value of following the word of God.'
  },
  {
    question: 'From the book of Esther - who was queen Esther’s relative?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Shimei' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Mordecai' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Hagai' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Xerxes' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: 'From Esther 2 - Mordecai had raised his cousin Hadassah, otherwise known as Esther, since she had no father or mother.'
  },
  {
    question: 'According to Proverbs, where does knowledge begin?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Respect for God' },
      { id: 2, text: 'An honest life' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Fear of accidents' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Advice of friends' }
    ],
    answer: 1,
    note: 'Proverbs 1:7 - Start with God — the first step in learning is bowing down to God.'
  },
  {
    question: 'There’s an opportune time to do things, a right time for everything on the earth. Where are these famous verses found?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Esther 3' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Job 3' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Proverbs 3' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Ecclesiastes 3' }
    ],
    answer: 4,
    note: 'Ecclesiastes 3, the wise man talks about time - There is a right time for everything. A right time for birth and another for death ...'
  },
  {
    question: 'From the book of Nehemiah - what was Nehemiah profession?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Soldier' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Cupbearer to the king' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Builder' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Bodyguard for the prince' }
    ],
    answer: 2,
    note: 'From Nehemiah 1/2 - I was cupbearer to the king. At the hour for serving wine I brought it in and gave it to the king. I had never been hangdog in his presence before, so he asked me, “Why the long face? You’re not sick are you? Or are you depressed?”'
  },
  {
    question: 'In the often read story of the "Woman at the well", where did Jesus meet the Samaritan woman?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: 'Nain' },
      { id: 2, text: 'Judah' },
      { id: 3, text: 'Sychar' },
      { id: 4, text: 'Jerusalem' }
    ],
    answer: 3,
    note: 'From John 4 - Jesus had to pass through Samaria. He came into Sychar, a Samaritan village that bordered the field Jacob had given his son Joseph. Jacob’s well was still there.'
  },
  {
    question: 'Jesus raised Lazarus from the dead. How many days had passed since he was dead?',
    type: 'multiple_choice',
    options: [
      { id: 1, text: '2' },
      { id: 2, text: '3' },
      { id: 3, text: '4' },
      { id: 4, text: '5' }
    ],
    answer: 3,
    note: 'From John 11 - When Jesus finally got there, he found Lazarus already four days dead. Martha said, “Master, if you’d been here, my brother wouldn’t have died. Even now, I know that whatever you ask God he will give you.”'
  }
]
